Finding Aid for Glenn C. Gillespie papers, 1905-1959
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Glenn C. Gillespie papers 1905-1959
Gillespie, Glenn C.(Glenn Carlton), 1885-
2 linear ft.,1 oversize folder, 2 film reels, 2 DVDs and digital video files
9182 Aa 2; UAm
Opinions written as judge, June 1, 1921-December 4, 1935 (7 volumes); photograph albums; account book, 1908-1910; miscellaneous clippings, citations, and correspondence and motion pictures
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received in several accessions begining in 1993 through the Eunice Hendrix Trust.. Donor no. 6548.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Glenn C. Gillespie was born on a farm in Addison Township, Oakland County Michigan, June 10, 1885. He worked as a telegraph operator to as young ma before graduating from the University of Michigan Law School in 1910. He opened a law practice I Pontiac, Michigan where he resided for the rest of his life. In 1921 he named a judge of the Sixth Judicial Circuit of Michigan. He served as s judge for 15 years before returning to private practice. He was recognized a leading authority on criminal law and procedure. He was a founding member and first president of the State Bar Association.
Gillespie was an avid hunter fisherman and aviation enthusiast. He died March 11, 1959 in automobile accident in Bristow, Oklahoma.
The Gillespie papers consist of clippings and miscellaneous items relating to his legal career and articles on his death, photographs, judicial opinions and films.
The Photographs consist of portraits and s composite photos of Oakland County Bench and Bar, 1924 and 1950, and a folder of copy prints of photos from the two albums. The albums contain numerous images of hunting and fishing scenes, many frorm Houghton Lake and the Au Sable River, oil rigs in Genesee county, the Detroit Ski Club ski jump in Rochester, Michigan, photos of the First and Second Michigan Air Tours, 1929 and 1931, view of Mackinaw City, Mich storefronts, 1917, Ranger, Texas, street views and oil rigs, 1919, vacation at Isle Royale, Mich., 1935, and a trip to the Soo Locks and Tahquamenon Falls.
The Judicial Opinions Series includes all of he opinions Gillespie wrote as a member of the Sixth Judicial Circuit Court of Michigan, 1921-1934
The Motion Pictures series consists of two 16mm films documenting portions of the First and Second Michigan Air Tours, 1929-1930, including footage of airplanes and aerial views of Michigan scenes; includes views of Governor Fred Green, the airship Graf Zeppelin, and Mackinac Island The films were digitized in 2011 and are now available on DVD or as streaming files (on request).
Subjects:
Gillespie, Glenn C. (Glenn Carlton), 1885-; Judges--Michigan--Oakland County.; Michigan. Circuit Court (Oakland County)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Airplanes.; Airships.; Gillespie, Glenn C. (Glenn Carlton), 1885-; Graf Zeppelin (Airship); Green, Fred Warren, 1872-1936.; Mackinac Island (Mich.); Deer hunting--Michigan.; Fishing--Michigan.; Houghton Lake (Mich.); Hunting--Michigan.; Isle Royale (Mich.); Mackinaw City (Mich.); Oil wells--Michigan--Genesee County.; Oil wells--Texas--Ranger.; Ranger (Tex.)
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.; DVDs.
- Papers
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Account Book, 1980-1910 (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Portraits and group photos (Box 1)
    - Copy prints from photo album (Box 1)
  - Photo Albums, 2 vols.
    - Ca. 1906-1922 (Box 1)
    - Ca. 1921-1935 (Box 1)
  - Judicial Opinions, 1921-1934, 7 vols. (Box 2)
- Motion Pictures
  - Motion picture of First Michigan Air Tour, 1929, 9182-1
    - Original, 16mm film, pos., b/w, silent, 00:11:22
    - Use Copy:, DVD (Box D-1)
    - Streaming File: 9182-1, flash-flv
  - Motion picture of Second Michigan Air Tour, 1931, 9182-2
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, silent, 00:03:27
    - Use Copy:, DVD (Box D-1)
    - Streaming File: 9182-2, flash-flv